PAUL DAVIDSON WEB DEVELOPER

- paul@paulrossdavidson.com
- paulrossdavSeattle, WA paulrossdavidson.com
- in paul-davidson
- PaulRossDavidson

With a passion for building web apps using the most simple, short and clear code solutions, I am gaining experience with Angular.js and other technologies. My mission is to become a top teir developer. I look forward to merging my interests in travel, outdoor recreation and new technologies with web based solutions at every chance I

When not coding, I enjoy DIY projects, economics and travelling.

Skills

FRONT END

Angular.js

HTML5

Material-UI

Bootstrap

JavaScript

BACK END

MongoDB

Node.js

Express

PostgreSQL

Ruby

Sails

Rails

DEVELOPMENT

Git

Pair Programming Project Management

Education

University of Alaska, Anchorage **BA BUS 2011**

Employment

General Assemly

Seattle, WA

Full Stack Web Developer

Jun 2015 to Sep 2015

This program fulfilled a long growing passion for web development through intensive, skills acquisition. For 12 weeks it was hands on project work 20 hours per week and learned cutting edge technology from experienced professionals for 40 hours per week in a startup/co-working space. This program gave me industry best practices from professionals.

GearSpoke Anchorage, AK

CEO

Mar 2011 to Apr 2014

Continuously improved company direction and site development by asking the right questions to potential users, looking at data, listening to mentors and becoming an expert in the sharing economy. Created, energized and managed a cohesive six person team with development and marketing sub teams. Built a high impact, low cost, marketing plan and owned it's execution. Created mutually beneficial marketing relationships with local companies. Put on events for target market. Presented the company and the sharing economy at local speaking events. Successfully implemented remote working days.

BP Oil Exploration

Anchorage, AK

Buyer -Rotating Equpment

Mar 2011 to Jun 2013

Worked as mid value buyer (25k-250k) for rotating equipment for BP Exploration Alaska. Utilized good communication to coordinate working with remote co-workers. Toured warehouses and local manufacturing spaces and met with various suppliers. Volunteered as the emergency response coordinator for the 6th floor at BP headquarters, completing a suite of training classes.

Projects

PrepperPrepper

Built with three other developers, PrepperPrepper is a Node-Express-Angular app for people to get a synopsis of what emergencies they should prepare for based on their location. The app goes further and gamifies the preparedness process with a score and leaderboard.

OverlandIt

I built this Node-Express-MongoDB app using an Angular-Material front end. It is a site that aggregates expedition vehicles for sale.

Asteroids

This is a lightweight two player game built in JavaScript. Block the asteroid to stave off the apocalypse and get a higher score!

Activities

Drone Builder · Hacker

Iul 2003 to Current

I build RC aircraft out of recycled materials. I also do aerial photography and fly through a video downlink. I have a lot of fun!